Umamusume.
They are born to run.
They inherit the names of horses from another world,
whose histories were sometimes tragic
and sometimes wonderful, and run ever forward.
That is... their fate.
No one knows how the races waiting
in the futures of these Umamusume will end.
But they will continue to run,
aiming only toward the goal in front of them.
Avec Blaze is leading the pack,
but the gap behind her is quickly closing.
The runners are making their way through the final turn.
Which of the Umamusume running today will win
the Yayoi Sho and advance full speed onto the Classic Road?
Now, everyone has entered the homestretch.
Narita Top Road is closing in!
Narita Top Road is moving up from the outside!
Admire Vega lingers behind the pack.
You can do it, Prez!
Go!
I want to live up... to everyone's expectations.
I'm going to win!
Narita Top Road pushes from the outside!
Today's favorite to win, Admire Vega,
has begun to catch up!
Admire Vega is advancing quickly!
I can't lose... for her sake as well!
Admire Vega cuts through to second place!
I knew she would end up right behind me...
But I...
Admire Vega has caught up, yet...
Was it enough to take the lead?
Narita Top Road crosses the finish!
Narita Top Road has won!
An absolutely stunning victory!
Way to go, Top Road!
That was super amazing!
You ran your heart out!
You're so cool, Top Road!
Hashiridashita hitomi ga
Eyes that being to run,
mezasuno wa ichiban shika nai
aspiring to nothing more than number one
Glorious one moment
shouri de shika tsukamenai kiseki
a miracle that can only achieve victory
Umamusume: Pretty Derby
Road to the Top
Onaji toki wo irodotte
Coloring the very moment,
kagayaki tachi ga jibun wo miteru kara
because the bright lights are looking at me.
Genkai nante kimerarenai
I can't set limits,
unmei ga raibaru
destiny is my rival
Believe Dream
Akogare wa mou chousen ni nattanda
My longing has already become a challenge
Believe Pride
Butai ni tatsun da tte tsuyoi kanjou
I have a strong feeling that I'll be on the stage
Believe Yell
Kotaetai kimochi mo dakishime
Embracing the feeling of wanting to respond
Ima mirai e geeto ga hiraiteku
Now the door of the future opens,
reesu ga hajimatteku
the race begins
Issei taafu ni fuku kaze ni kawaru
It will become the wind blowing on the grass at once
mune no oku no atsui omoi wa
The passion in my heart,
dare ni mo yuzure wa shinai kara
I won't let anyone take it away from me.
Kakenuketeku sokudo wa
The speed at
watashi tachi no sakebi nanda
which we run is our cry
Kisoiau hodo ni hibiiteku
The more we race, the more it resonates
Running to the top!
Eikou to iu gooru e to mukau kiseki
The miracle of running towards the goal of glory
Episode 1: A Dream's Starting Gate
Here I go!
The arc is so large...
I can do better.
One more time!
Geez...
I told her to skip the morning session today.
Still strugglin' with the small corners I see...
Time to wrap it up.
Oh, Trainer-san. Good morning!
And why are you out here?
Pushing yourself the day after a race?
I'm sorry!
I can't seem to relax, knowing that
I'm finally moving on to the big races.
The big races, eh?
I've been waiting for this moment my entire life.
The first race for a Classic Triple Crown title, the Satsuki Sho.
I'm going to win no matter what!
You seem pretty fired up.
It's part of my promise!
To stand at the top of the Twinkle Series...
I used to be a nobody,
but it's all thanks to an amazing
trainer-san that I've come this far.
It's time for me to repay that favor!
You know that you're going to be facing her again then, right?
Morning!
Good morning.
Oh, Top Road-san!
Good morning!
Mornin'!
Someone's chipper today.
Not so surprising, really.
Good morning!
Oh hey, it's Prez!
Morning!
Oh, right. There's homework to collect today.
Everyone, please stack your notebooks over here.
Okay!
Hey, Prez. Could you help me with some of this stuff later?
Sure, I'd be happy to help if I can!
You're a lifesaver.
Oh, Ayabe-san!
Good morning!
Morning... Here's my homework.
Thanks! I'll add it to the pile.
Is something wrong?
You're hurt...
Huh?
There's a scrape right there.
Wow, I somehow didn't even realize it!
It's because you were pushing yourself so hard so early in the morning.
Come with me.
Thank you so much!
Letting these things go untreated is no good.
You're right, I'll be careful.
Oh right, so that must mean...
Were you also out doing
some training this morning?
I guess you saw me fall and
figured something might be wrong.
Yes, I did.
Are you training for the Satsuki Sho?
Yes.
And I don't plan to lose any longer.
Above all,
I'll be outrunning the first place winner of the Yayoi Sho.
I'm really glad to hear you say that. Especially you, of all people.
What do you mean by that?
You’re the ideal that I constantly strive for, Ayabe-san.
The ideal?
Yes.
You're always the favorite to win your races,
and your victory in your first graded race
wasn't even a matter of doubt...
I'm not even close to your level yet.
Knowing what I was up against during
the Yayoi Sho inspired me to run like I did.
We'll be racing again.
This time, at the Satsuki Sho!
Oh, I better get those notebooks over to the faculty room.
Thanks for patching me up, Ayabe-san!
I won't lose.
Not to her. Not to anyone.
Please, look on at me.
Look on at your sister.
The Umamusume enter the final turn.
After winning the Yayoi Sho, the Classic Ro—
Repay the favor, huh?
To think that she's come so far as to be able to say that...
Keep it up!
Thanks for taking the time to come watch.
Nah, it's the least I can do for
everything you've done for me. So...
Is that her?
Yes, she's my daughter.
Quite the spring in her step for someone her age.
Her footwork could use a bit of work, though.
She gets a bit of her pa's clumsiness.
Her character's pretty different from my own, though.
Her earnest nature never ceases to amaze me.
Being able to devote oneself to this kind of training is a talent in itself.
Bye-bye, Sensei.
Yes, goodbye now.
Be careful on your way home!
Top Road-san, you're still runnin'?
Yes, just a little longer!
I've got my race coming up!
Wow, Top Road sure is serious!
Good luck at the race!
We'll be cheerin' you on!
Cheering?
I'll do my best!
Go for it!
Keep it up, Top Road-san!
I can hear everyone's cheers...
I can't lose!
Narita Top Road crosses the finish!
Narita Top Road has won!
Huh? Training? Me?
And with a pro trainer?
D-Do you mean it?
What's wrong? Feeling shy?
Listen.
It's true that your running style is a bit rough.
Your racing skills aren't fully up to snuff either.
Still, I can tell that you
have what it takes to shine.
But I always get so nervous before a race...
I get so nervous and anxious...
That may be so,
but you always stand tall and go out there.
Right?
That's...
Yeah. I don't want to run away.
And you're really tough for doing that.
That's why everyone cheers you on.
That's why...
What do you say, Narita Top Road?
Wanna aim for the top
of the Twinkle Series with me?
She's come a long way since then...
To stand at the top of the Twinkle Series, though...
It's certainly become a realistic achievement for her.
Admire Vega advances from fourth to third place!
She takes second place!
Admire Vega just misses out on the lead!
We also have a certain someone here to worry about.
We'll be at a disadvantage if she has to make any major accelerations in the final stretch.
She's not great with small corners,
and finally...
There are a lot of worthy challengers to be wary of.
T.M. Opera O has broken away! T.M. Opera O is in the lead!
T.M. Opera O extends her lead from three lengths to four.
T.M. Opera O clears the goal! A dazzling third consecutive win, and her first graded race victory!
Incredible perseverance through such a crowded race agenda—what an achievement!
She'll likely be after a win at
the Japanese Derby next.
That will be an interesting race to watch after observing her performance here today.
2 months ago
Yes, good!
A-A-Amazing!
Didn't you just recover
from an injury? T-T-This time...
Look!
It would seem I have matched
the speed of light itself at last!
Oh no, I'm sorry! I pushed the wrong button.
It's quite all right, Doto.
Thanks to you, my victory at
tomorrow's maiden race is all but assured.
I'll be victorious tomorrow, and
he next time, and the next-next time!
I must boldly show everyone that I am up for the challenge!
Up to what challenge, exactly?
The Satsuki Sho.
A Classic race without me would be akin to La Traviata without Violetta.
I cannot let the audience down like that, can I?
T.M. Opera O! T.M. Opera O has won!
A consecutive victory for T.M. Opera O!
Once more, please.
Opera O-san!
Sorry about that.
You're pushing yourself way too hard.
You should really take a break.
I cannot abide the thought, Doto.
Persevering through anguish is exactly
what the audience wishes to see in my performance.
You can hear them, yes?
The cries of anticipation for my appearance. The shouts praising my glory!
The curtains are rising, Doto.
Therefore, I will prove it.
On that stage that is the Satsuki Sho,
I will prove that it is I who
deserves to play the leading role!
The cafeteria at lunchtime is as bustling as a premiere at La Scala.
Oh?
Oguri-san, would you allow me
to partake next to you?
Sure, no problem.
Please.
You put on a great display at
the Mainichi Hai the other day.
Thank you.
To think I had the attention of
an Umamusume of such caliber as yourself!
The Mainichi Hai is a race near
and dear to my heart.
Have you decided on your next race?
It's the Satsuki Sho, of course.
It is for that very reason I overcame such an arduous rotation of races.
The toll it took on my body
was not small, however.
It was exhausting.
But... even so...
Yeah, I think you should enter.
Receiving your approval is no small feat.
I believe you'd offer some serious competition.
Thank you, Oguri-san.
That inspires a tremendous
amount of confidence within me.
Ayabe-san!
What?
Are you really going out so late tonight too?
You're pushing yourself much more than usual.
I can't afford to lose anymore.
You should go to sleep.
I promise, I will win.
It's the only way I can make it up to you...
Prez!
Hang in there!
Ayabe-san's talent lies within the homestretch.
She'll be right on my tail as she blazes onward during her last spurt.
Right... here!
That was pretty much perfect.
Thanks!
I can't count out her own gains in the next race, though.
I'm gonna go for it again!
Just keep a cool head, all right?
I will!
It's that time of the year once again!
Welcome to the first race of the Classic Triple Crown series, the Satsuki Sho!
"Highly anticipated" would be an understatement this year.
Yeah, right,
and even though it's raining today, the excitement is palpable.
All eyes are on this year's favorite and second-favorite, Admire Vega
and Narita Top Road respectively.
It's pretty inconceivable that it will be anyone other than one of those two.
Ayabe-san...
It's time—
Welcome: Top Road-san, Ayabe-san!
To the grand performance of the first chapter in the Legend of the Centurial Overlord!
Opera O-san...
The Triple Crowns are only fit for me, T.M. Opera O!
Wouldn't you agree?
It's been truly amazing to see everything that you've accomplished, Opera O-san.
But I've been giving everything I've got to my training,
and I won't be letting my trainer and
everyone else who has supported me down.
I... won't losing!
Nakayama Racecourse, turf, 2,000 meters.
This year's Satsuki Sho features seventeen entrants.
The Satsuki Sho is the first race of the Classic Triple Crown series.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime challenge for these runners.
The Umamusume are making their way to the starting gate.
Opera O-san...
Admire Vega has entered the gate.
That calm demeanor is just one of the many reasons she is today's favorite to win.
Ayabe-san...
Narita Top Road is making
her way to the gate as well.
You can do it, Prez!
Fight on!
We know ya can do it!
Narita Top Road appears to be in top form,
and just listen to those cheers!
So this is... a GI race.
Don't lose your cool. You can do this.
Which of these runners will be taking home the first crown?
The race has started.
Every Umamusume is off to a good start.
Will Petit Folklore push forward?
Will she, or won't she?
Tropical Sky comes in from the inside...
Yes, that was a great start! In third place is Aqua Ocean, coming up rapidly to take the lead!
With Aqua Ocean in the lead,
the runners are approaching the first turn.
Our practice is payin' off in spades.
She's blocked in!
What can she do?
I've gotta break through...
No, not here. Not yet.
Paces are average across the board.
The pitch gradually increases as
the runners approach the third turn.
Tropical Sky takes the lead.
The runners will start to prepare to make their last spurts!
Me too!
Admire Vega is moving up!
Narita Top Road is in direct pursuit!
Coming out of the fourth turn are Admire Vega and Narita Top Road from the outside!
They've entered the final stretch!
Go for it, you two!
The shine of the Satsuki Sho crown is in their sights!
Admire Vega loses speed!
Ayabe-san?
This might be tough.
I won't lose! Everyone's expectations...
Trainer-san's dream!
Go!
Push through!
Go for it!
Narita Top Road bursts forth from the center! Narita Top Road!
I can do this! Just a little more!
Coming in from the far outside is T.M. Opera O!
T.M. Opera O is advancing fast!
This is some incredible acceleration!
And the winner is...
T.M. Opera O! T.M. Opera O has won the Satsuki Sho!
Sh-She did it! Opera O-san!
Unbelievable... Opera O-san has come so far.
I was so close...
I wanted to win this so badly...
I thought I had improved so much...
It's not enough...
Narita Top Road!
An exceptional performance!
Top Road was so awesome!
I'll keep cheering you on!
Prez!
No time for regrets.
I'm going to work even harder
to meet everyone's expectations.
I'll show you...
what I can do at the Japanese Derby!